A.N.Abishek

No.14, N.S.K Nagar, (1st Street, Bashyam Nagar), Chromepet, Chennai, India.

+91-7200483919 | anabishek@gmail.com | Github - AbishekNavukkarasan | Linkedin - AbishekNavukkarasan

Professional summary

A Passionate Interdisciplinary engineer with 2 Years of in-depth experience in Open Source development for Tech Startups. I design, make, weld, fabricate, solder and code. Looking for a challenging career which demands the best of my technical and analytical skills, and helps me in broadening and enhancing my current skills and knowledge.

Experience

R&D Intern / Lema Labs Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

December 2017 - Present, Chennai

Develop and design Robotic kits from concept and proof of principles to specifications and implementation. Coordinate with internal or external engineering teams on new designs and capability improvement and validation.

Project Intern / RapidFab 3D Engineering Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

January 2018 - May 2018, Chennai

Development of SCARA Robotic arm 3D Printer; working from initial concept and design to production phase, machining, prototyping, testing, and release.

Team Lead / Team Algol

August 2016 - December 2016, Chennai

Led a cross-functional engineering team in the design and implementation of a precision device capable of identifying the existence of life on the lunar surface.

R&D Hardware Intern / Rent&Make Virtual Makerspace

July 2016 - December 2016, Chennai

Researched, Designed, Developed and Optimised Open source hardware. Was responsible for managing and deployment of 4 major products to customers. Created and managed fabrication budgets and operating specifications.

Courses

Kaizen Robotics Program / Lema Labs Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

July - August 2016, Chennai

Robotics development using embedded C.

CAD Using CATIA / AU-FRG Institute for CAD/CAM, Anna University

December 2015, Chennai

A Computer-aided Designing course using CATIA.

Education

B.E, **Mechanical Engineering** / Anna University

6.55 CGPA - August 2014 - May 2018

Higher Sec. Certificate / Zion Matriculation Higher Sec. School

66.75% - March 2014 - Selaiyur, Chennai

Secondary School Certificate / Zion Matriculation School

79.2% - April 2012 - Sembakkam, Chennai

Skills:

Design and Analysis:

Dassault Systèmes: CATIA, SolidWorks AutoDesk: AutoCAD, Fusion 360

Analysis:

Simscale, Ansys

Programming Language:

Python

Machine Learning libraries: Numpy, Scipy, Pandas, Sci-kit Learn Deep Learning libraries: Fast.ai, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Keras

Projects:

SCARA Robotic Arm 3D Printer

Final Year Project December 2017 - May 2018, Chennai

Lab2Moon

Team Algol/Team Indus August 2016 - December 2016, Chennai

Autonomous Tractor

Autodesk India Design Week November 2017 - December 2017, Chenna

Improvised Prusa i3 3D Printer

Design and Fabrication Project
December 2016 - March 2017, Chennai

Areas of Interest:

- **★** Robotics
- ★ Deep Learning
- ★ Internet of Things
- ★ 3D Printing
- ★ Space technologies

Personal Details:

DOB: 19-08-1996 Languages: English, Tamil.

Extra-Curriculars:

- NCC "C" Certified as of September 2017
- Student Ambassador of Kurukshetra 2k17
- Participated and Won prizes in several National level Symposiums and Student Conventions.
- Public Relations Head and Web Developer of Mars2k17, 19th National Level symposium conducted by the Department of Mechanical engineering, Sri Sairam Engineering College.
- Active Participation in Workshops and meetups of Local online communities, related to IoT, 3D Printing, Makerspace, Al/Machine learning.
- Was one of the finalists of Autodesk India Design week 2017 competition.